<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Logstore on vurt </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://vurt.co.uk/projects/logstore/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 22:02:55 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a log store</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/project/building-a-log-store</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 22:02:55 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/project/building-a-log-store</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had a wood burning stove installed which meant that I needed somewhere to store all the logs I&amp;rsquo;ll be burning. Rather than spend a lot of money on a professionally made log store, I decided to make my own, because hey, I own a hammer and a saw, how hard can it be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sketched a rough plan on the bag of an envelope then headed down to my nearest large hardware retailer and picked up some supplies:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_113251.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_113251-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_113251&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
I decided to use a 6&amp;rsquo;x3&amp;rsquo; lattice fence panel as the back of the log store because I was feeling lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a simple base, using five cross pieces to take the weight of the logs and form the feet of the store:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_121656.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_121656-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_121656&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the base was done, it was time to make the sides. Since I was using a 6&amp;rsquo;x3&amp;rsquo; panel for the back, I made the rear uprights just over 3&amp;rsquo; tall and the front ones around 4&amp;rsquo;. Throw in a couple of braces and then nail the back in place and I&amp;rsquo;m left with this: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_131014.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_131014-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_131014&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the roof, I added horizontal beams to the front and rear uprights then added 4 rafters, making sure to accurately measure and cut the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birdsmouth_joint&#34;&gt;birdsmouth joints&lt;/a&gt;. I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t sloppily mark and then eyeball the cuts with a junior hacksaw, oh no:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_142355.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_142355-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_142355&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; I made sure to leave an overhang so the finished roof would extend in front of the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the roof out of featheredge fence boards, nailing them to the rafters and making sure they overlap each other by around 50%. Fence boards were also used for the sides, makign sure to leave gaps to allow for air circulation: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_161531.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_161531-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_161531&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was the store made, then it was just a case of moving it into position then stacking all the logs up, making sure to leave room for the cat&amp;rsquo;s house since the store is going against the wall where the cat house normally sits:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130217_143339.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130217_143339-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130217_143339&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I&amp;rsquo;m pretty pleased with it, it may not be perfect but it does the job and it looks the part. I&amp;rsquo;ve filled it with just over 1 cubic metre of logs and there&amp;rsquo;s room for a bit more should I need it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>