<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on vurt </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://vurt.co.uk/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 09:41:07 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restore Cylinder Mower</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/restore_cylinder_mower</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 09:41:07 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/restore_cylinder_mower</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get an old cylinder mower (old battered one, but running seen on ebay for #60) and do it up but painted in hot-rod style?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re-sharpen cutting blade and get working smoothly but make it look awesome with gloss black colour-scheme (red detailing - maybe flame motif on grass bin?)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Power Shed</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/solar_power_shed</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 09:40:50 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/solar_power_shed</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Add solar panel system to shed to provide power down at the patio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would need a solar panel (50W?), charge controller, battery (deep cycle lead acid) and an 240V inverter to run mains powered devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could get a submersible pump (are 12V ones available?) to put in the water barrels to use to water the veg patches better. Could this be automated with Raspi/arduino, solenoids and soil moisture sensors to provide automatic watering? Could tie it in to weather forecasts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get EL-wire and fix to outline of shed and power from the battery to provide funky lighting at the patio during the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site Workflow</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/post/new_website</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 10:32:25 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/post/new_website</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve updated my website to have a new look and feel, obviously based on a bootstrap theme because I&amp;rsquo;m no designer and I&amp;rsquo;m lazy. However, the biggest change is that I&amp;rsquo;ve moved away from using Wordpress to a static site generator called &lt;a href=&#34;http://hugo.spf13.com&#34; title=&#34;Hugo, A Fast &amp;amp; Modern Static Website Engine&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped using Wordpress because I was sick of constantly having to upgrade it and I was equally sick of the constant attempts at comment spam. Even though I had various anti-spam measures in place and comments had to be approved before getting posted - every day I&amp;rsquo;d get half a dozen random user accounts generated by spam-bots. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t need that kind of overhead and hassle I decided to switch to a static site generator instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the change in technologies, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to change the way I use this site in an effort to post more frequently than my previous average of once or twice a year. So my main intention is to use this site as a dumping ground for ideas I have and as a build log for my various projects. Traditionally I&amp;rsquo;ve had lots of ideas scribbled down on bits of paper and in various notebooks that I then forget about. Hopefully by making things public the ideas may provide inspiration for others even if I don&amp;rsquo;t do anything with them myself. As for project build logs - I have a number of historical projects I aim to get written up and some on going projects that I&amp;rsquo;ll add to as time goes by (hopefully).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown Bags</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/brown_bags</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 08:00:28 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/brown_bags</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Ideas for filling in empty Brown Bag slots&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of thoughts on how to fill empty brown bag slots at work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Show Dev videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trialled this at short notice yesterday by showing a Google I/O video &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/yC7Pf3Ad9t8?list=PL_aeGNMU1zXNVihdLzClBhTOtFxzj5eWi&#34;&gt;Casting to the future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an easy way to fill a slot and there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of choice, even just from the Google I/O videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could extend this by having a &amp;ldquo;Vote for the next video&amp;rdquo; option?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Give Talks Myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use it as an opportunity to get loads of presenting practice myself. Give a talk on any current subject of interest. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to be long, even just 20 - 30 minutes would suffice. Would be good way to develop the habit of creating content and for formalising thoughts I have on various topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People may get sick of me presenting all the time but that would hopefully just spur them on to do a talk themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could tie my presentations in with blog posts (cut down version on blackpepper.co.uk linking to full version/authoritative version on my site). Again, good practice at content generation and getting in to the habit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Bot</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/tweitter_bot</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 01:27:54 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/tweitter_bot</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;n-gram/markov chain driven bot that combines tweets by others on given tags into random posts of its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively could start with known dictionary and add all responses to its dictionary, gradually evolving its output.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing Federation</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/publishing_tool</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 09:52:12 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/idea/publishing_tool</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Tool to automate web publishing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a static site generation tool, how can I easily publish to other channels such as Facebook or twitter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool should have a configurable list of publishers, along with their characteristics (e.g. API key, min/max length, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When run, new posts would be automatically published to the configured channels along with a link back to the master web page produced by the static site generation tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://indiewebcamp.com/POSSE&#34;&gt;http://indiewebcamp.com/POSSE&lt;/a&gt; POSSE indieweb federation strategy. Could I develop a hugo extension to do this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewriting history with git</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/rewriting-history-with-git</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 09:15:40 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/rewriting-history-with-git</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when working with git branches, you&amp;rsquo;ll find you need to rewrite history to correct a mistake. For example you squashed your commits into one and pushed them but then realised you&amp;rsquo;d missed something from the squash and need to do it again. Now, while you can perform the git rebase -i again and make the changes locally, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to push this back to origin as your branches have diverged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way of working around this is to delete the remote branch and then push your branch again, essentially overwriting the remote with your version of history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t something that should be done without forethought though, as it has implications for anyone else who may be using the branch but if no one else has done any additional work on the branch then this is relatively safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process for deleting the remote branch is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push origin :branchname&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pushes null to the remote branch, effectively deleting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you want to push your local branch to origin, tracking it in the process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push -u origin branchname&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your branch will now be on origin and your local branch will be tracking it correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone else who has used the branch will want to &lt;code&gt;git reset --hard origin/branchname&lt;/code&gt; in order to get your changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend doing some more reading on this matter before doing it as it&amp;rsquo;s likely that this is all sorts of wrong in the majority of situations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a log store</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/project/building-a-log-store</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 22:02:55 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/project/building-a-log-store</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had a wood burning stove installed which meant that I needed somewhere to store all the logs I&amp;rsquo;ll be burning. Rather than spend a lot of money on a professionally made log store, I decided to make my own, because hey, I own a hammer and a saw, how hard can it be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sketched a rough plan on the bag of an envelope then headed down to my nearest large hardware retailer and picked up some supplies:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_113251.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_113251-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_113251&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
I decided to use a 6&amp;rsquo;x3&amp;rsquo; lattice fence panel as the back of the log store because I was feeling lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a simple base, using five cross pieces to take the weight of the logs and form the feet of the store:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_121656.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_121656-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_121656&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the base was done, it was time to make the sides. Since I was using a 6&amp;rsquo;x3&amp;rsquo; panel for the back, I made the rear uprights just over 3&amp;rsquo; tall and the front ones around 4&amp;rsquo;. Throw in a couple of braces and then nail the back in place and I&amp;rsquo;m left with this: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_131014.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_131014-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_131014&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the roof, I added horizontal beams to the front and rear uprights then added 4 rafters, making sure to accurately measure and cut the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birdsmouth_joint&#34;&gt;birdsmouth joints&lt;/a&gt;. I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t sloppily mark and then eyeball the cuts with a junior hacksaw, oh no:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_142355.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_142355-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_142355&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; I made sure to leave an overhang so the finished roof would extend in front of the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the roof out of featheredge fence boards, nailing them to the rafters and making sure they overlap each other by around 50%. Fence boards were also used for the sides, makign sure to leave gaps to allow for air circulation: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_161531.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_161531-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_161531&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was the store made, then it was just a case of moving it into position then stacking all the logs up, making sure to leave room for the cat&amp;rsquo;s house since the store is going against the wall where the cat house normally sits:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130217_143339.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130217_143339-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130217_143339&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I&amp;rsquo;m pretty pleased with it, it may not be perfect but it does the job and it looks the part. I&amp;rsquo;ve filled it with just over 1 cubic metre of logs and there&amp;rsquo;s room for a bit more should I need it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messing about with MRI Data</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/messing-about-with-mri-data</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 15:25:40 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/messing-about-with-mri-data</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve had 2 MRI scans of my left knee as part of ongoing treatment/diagnosis for chronic pain. When discussing my treatment with the consultant, I was intrigued by the images produced by the scanner - detailed images of the inside of my knee from several angles. And thanks to the Data Protection Act, the hospital has to provide me with the data from thescans if I ask for it. So, one quick query at the MRI department, I handed over £10 (The nominal fee to prevent frivolous requests) and walked away with a CD containing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DICOM&#34;&gt;DICOM&lt;/a&gt; image data from both my scans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I have the data but what can I do with it? Surely I&amp;rsquo;ll need some proprietary medical imaging software to view it with? Well on the CD was a windows based viewer program but as a Linux user it&amp;rsquo;s no good to me. Thankfully because DICOM is a ubiquitous standard there are masses of tools available, including many open source offerings. I ended up trying both &lt;a href=&#34;http://ginkgo-cadx.com/en/&#34;&gt;Ginkgocadx&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slicer.org/&#34;&gt;Slicer3D&lt;/a&gt;. Both worked as expected but I ended up sticking with Ginkgocadx - it clicked with me more than Slicer, although that may just be because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to read the Slicer tutorials. Both applications let you view, manipulate and edit the image sequences and they can produce 3Dmodels from the scan data as well, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t explored that option properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve just colourised and converted the image data to make it easier to read and then produced the following pointless (yet strangely engrossing) animated gifs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bones, muscles, tendons and veins in glorious tango-vision!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/2013/01/18/messing-about-with-mri-data/lt_ax_t2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lt_ax_t2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;lt_ax_t2&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/2013/01/18/messing-about-with-mri-data/lt_cor_pd/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lt_cor_pd.gif&#34; alt=&#34;lt_cor_pd&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/2013/01/18/messing-about-with-mri-data/lt_sag_t2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lt_sag_t2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;lt_sag_t2&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These images came from the most recent scan, I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to convert the ones from before my arthroscopy but I&amp;rsquo;ll do that soon and then see if I can spot the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you fancy having a go yourself but haven&amp;rsquo;t had an MRI scan, then drop me a line and I&amp;rsquo;ll send you an anonymised version of my data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January Frost</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/january-frost</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 18:00:41 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/january-frost</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702198165/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7001/6702198165_cbe590a398.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img_0001_04 by gpaterson&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702198165/&#34;&gt;img_0001_04&lt;/a&gt;, a photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/&#34;&gt;gpaterson&lt;/a&gt; on Flickr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went out for a photography walk this morning, after a heavy frost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one turned out rather well I think, might be a candidate for my calendar project&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of others:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702191269/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7023/6702191269_08d8a84ab1_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img_0001_02&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702189313/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7017/6702189313_dd31743099_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img_0001_07&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702182167/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7143/6702182167_e2721127f7_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img_0001&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bill-a-soup recipe</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/bill-a-soup-recipe</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 13:34:29 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/bill-a-soup-recipe</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my recipe for delicious bill-a-soup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;450 g broccoli, cut into florets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;175 g  grated cheddar cheese&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;175 g potatoes, chopped&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 medium onion, chopped&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;750 ml chicken stock&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 tablespoon sunflower oil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;pinch Salt and pepper&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;frac12; teaspoon sugar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put the stock in a pan and bring to the boil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour the oil into a large saucepan and fry  the onion gently to soften it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the potatoes to the pan and stir.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the sugar and stock and cook for 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the broccoli and cook until tender, season well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blend the soup in a food processor until smooth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour the soup back into the saucepan,  and stir in the grated cheese.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serve when the cheese has melted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apt behind a proxy</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/apt-behind-a-proxy</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 10:11:56 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/apt-behind-a-proxy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At work, we have to run all our web traffic through an NTLM authenticated proxy, which is a bit of a pain on Linux, requiring us to make use of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cntlm.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;cntlm proxy.&lt;/a&gt; We run this proxy locally on each linux machine (to prevent all traffic appearing as if it comes from one user in the logs), which is fine, but it does cause one or two issues with apt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally I&amp;rsquo;d run apt as &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get ...&lt;/code&gt; but it seems as if the proxy environment variables don&amp;rsquo;t get propagated to the command running under sudo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To work around this, you need to configure apt directly to use a proxy. To do this, create a file in the &lt;code&gt;/etc/apt/apt.conf.d&lt;/code&gt; directory called &lt;code&gt;00proxy&lt;/code&gt;. The file should contain the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;Acquire {
    Retries &amp;quot;0&amp;quot;;
    HTTP {
        Proxy &amp;quot;http://localhost:5865&amp;quot;;
    }
};
&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all apt commands should run successfully through the proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 10.04 Ambiance theme issues with Firefox</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-10-04-ambiance-theme-issues-with-firefox</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 14:20:01 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-10-04-ambiance-theme-issues-with-firefox</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across an interesting issue concerning the default Ubuntu 10.04 Ambiance theme and read only inputs in Firefox today. Basically the foreground and background colours for disabled/read-only input fields are the same, meaning that you can&amp;rsquo;t actually read what&amp;rsquo;s in the fields. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example screen shot from an internal web app I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wmfs.net/&#34;&gt;my employers&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_112&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Disabled inputs in Firefox with the Ubuntu Ambiance theme&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/disabled_inputs_ambiance_crop.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/disabled_inputs_ambiance_crop-300x118.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s what it looks like when using the New Wave theme in Ubuntu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_113&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Disabled inputs in Firefox using the New Wave theme&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/disabled_inputs_new_wave_theme_cropped.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/disabled_inputs_new_wave_theme_cropped-300x118.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue caused me a few moments of panic when I thought I&amp;rsquo;d broken the app - I was glad it was just a theme glitch! I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to using New Wave for the time being until I can figure out how to get the Ambiance theme to behave properly without screwing the rest of the system colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (2010-05-27):&lt;/strong&gt; Ok, so this turns out to be actually caused by a strange coincidence meaning that our CSS style for disabled inputs had exactly the same colour as the disabled text in the Ambience theme. Since the res of our users are running Windows and IE, it&amp;rsquo;s not a problem. It only affects us developers using Ubuntu :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 10.04 64 bit Eclipse 3.5 Native Proxy support</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-10-04-64-bit-eclipse-3-5-native-proxy-support</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 15:07:31 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-10-04-64-bit-eclipse-3-5-native-proxy-support</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eclipse is a great IDE and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it day to day for a number of years now. However when I recently got a new laptop at work and installed Ubuntu 10.04 on to it, I ran into a problem with the Proxy configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At work, I&amp;rsquo;m stuck behind an NTLM authenticated proxy which I can get my system talking to thanks to running &lt;a href=&#34;http://cntlm.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;cntlm&lt;/a&gt; locally and setting the gnome proxy settings to point to that. On my previous laptop, I was running 32bit Ubuntu and Eclipse just automatically picked up the native proxy info and worked fine. It turns out that this functionality isn&amp;rsquo;t available by default in the 64bit version of Eclipse 3.5. Despite having the option to select &amp;ldquo;Native&amp;rdquo; in the Network Connections preferences in Eclipse, no values are picked up and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect to the outside world to install the extra features I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the solution is to grab the native proxy library from the forthcoming 3.6 version of Eclipse and install it into 3.5, as explained in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/show_bug.cgi?id=273072&#34;&gt;eclipse bug&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did that using the Ubuntu supported version of Eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download the 64 bit Linux version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/packages/release/helios/m6&#34;&gt;Eclipse Classic 3.6.0&lt;/a&gt; (M6 at the time of writing)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extract it locally and copy the file &lt;code&gt;plugins/org.eclipse.core.net.linux.x86_64_1.1.0.I20091106-0506.jar&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/eclipse/dropins&lt;/code&gt; (you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have to create the dropins directory first).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;/etc/eclipse.ini&lt;/code&gt; to include the following: &lt;code&gt;-Dorg.eclipse.core.net.enableGnome&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delete the eclipse 3.6 directory unless you have a pressing need to keep it around ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you next start eclipse, the Network Connections preferences will be prepopulated with the gnome proxy settings. It took me a while to figure this out, and I&amp;rsquo;ll no doubt need to do it again sometime, so this post is mostly for my own benefit, but hopefully someone else will find it useful too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bootnote: You may be wondering why I didn&amp;rsquo;t just install 3.6 and run that. Well mainly because it&amp;rsquo;s not fully supported by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springsource.com/products/sts&#34;&gt;SpringSource Tool Suite&lt;/a&gt; and also it&amp;rsquo;d mean looking after upgrades and dependencies myself. I&amp;rsquo;d rather have apt handle all that for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Lucid 10.04 Active Directory Woes</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-lucid-10-04-active-directory-woes</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 14:51:45 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-lucid-10-04-active-directory-woes</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was looking forward to the launch of Lucid Lynx as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/testing/lucid/beta2#Major%20new%20version%20of%20likewise-open&#34;&gt;one of the main features being touted&lt;/a&gt; was improved support for joining an Active Directory domain, in the form of Likewise-open. Now this isn&amp;rsquo;t something that most users will care about, but in a corporate environment, allowing users to login to Ubuntu using the same credentials as they use on their windows machines is pretty important. Previously I&amp;rsquo;d set things up manually by configuring Samba and Winbind, but that was a pain in the backside, so Likewise-open was an appealing option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I&amp;rsquo;ve been very disappointed so far. It seems that the version of Likewise-open that ships with Kucid, has a number of glaring bugs that make it virtually pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, there is &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/likewise-open/+bug/534629&#34;&gt;no support for a default domain&lt;/a&gt;. This means that the user has to always log in as user.name@domain or domain\user.name which is a pain. It&amp;rsquo;s not a show stopper but it is trivial to set up using samba, so why can&amp;rsquo;t Likewise support it? Well, Likewise claims to support it, via a registry setting, it&amp;rsquo;s just that it&amp;rsquo;s broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/likewise-open/+bug/572271&#34;&gt;broken credential caching&lt;/a&gt;. Laptops aren&amp;rsquo;t always connected to the domain, so any solution needs to be able to cache credentials to let the user log in when they&amp;rsquo;re out and about. It turns out that the default cache timeout in Likewise is 4 hours. And there&amp;rsquo;s no way to change that. 4 Hours! So that means when you take your laptop home with you at night, intending to work at home the enxt day, you faced with the fact that you can&amp;rsquo;t log in in the morning, or even later that evening. How handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until these issues can be resolved, I&amp;rsquo;m going to purge Likewise and resort to the Samba config method. It&amp;rsquo;s long winded, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s tried and tested and I can actually configure it to work how I need it to. Who knows, maybe Meerkat will have working Likewise, it&amp;rsquo;s just a shame Canonical were touting it as a big improvement in Lucid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, and on a side note, when I upgraded my netbook from 9.10 to 10.04, it killed my wifi and lost the nice netbook remix clutter UI. Ho hum. Time to do a clean install and see if that fixes things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong - I&amp;rsquo;m still a big Ubuntu and Linux fan, I just would have liked this launch to have gone a bit smoother&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>