<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Posts on vurt </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://vurt.co.uk/post/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 10:32:25 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site Workflow</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/post/new_website</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 10:32:25 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/post/new_website</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve updated my website to have a new look and feel, obviously based on a bootstrap theme because I&amp;rsquo;m no designer and I&amp;rsquo;m lazy. However, the biggest change is that I&amp;rsquo;ve moved away from using Wordpress to a static site generator called &lt;a href=&#34;http://hugo.spf13.com&#34; title=&#34;Hugo, A Fast &amp;amp; Modern Static Website Engine&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped using Wordpress because I was sick of constantly having to upgrade it and I was equally sick of the constant attempts at comment spam. Even though I had various anti-spam measures in place and comments had to be approved before getting posted - every day I&amp;rsquo;d get half a dozen random user accounts generated by spam-bots. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t need that kind of overhead and hassle I decided to switch to a static site generator instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the change in technologies, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to change the way I use this site in an effort to post more frequently than my previous average of once or twice a year. So my main intention is to use this site as a dumping ground for ideas I have and as a build log for my various projects. Traditionally I&amp;rsquo;ve had lots of ideas scribbled down on bits of paper and in various notebooks that I then forget about. Hopefully by making things public the ideas may provide inspiration for others even if I don&amp;rsquo;t do anything with them myself. As for project build logs - I have a number of historical projects I aim to get written up and some on going projects that I&amp;rsquo;ll add to as time goes by (hopefully).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>