<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Ginger-Beer on vurt </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://vurt.co.uk/projects/ginger-beer/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 15 Jun 2005 16:46:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Make Ginger Beer</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/project/gingerbeer</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2005 16:46:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/project/gingerbeer</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I fancied a nice cool drink the other night, but I&amp;rsquo;m fed up with cola, lemonade and juices.
I prefer a &amp;ldquo;drier&amp;rdquo; soft drink, and one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make you want to scrub your teeth
immediately after drinking. So I decided to make myself some ginger beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hang on, why didn&amp;rsquo;t you just buy some ginger beer?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; I imagine you asking me. Well, most  commercially produced ginger beer is far too sweet and not gingery enough for my taste,  that is why. And I was bored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;rsquo;s what I used to make a delicious ginger beverage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 litre bottle of still mineral water&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;large chunk of root ginger (you need 1½ to 2 tablespoons of grated ginger)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 lemon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 cup of sugar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;¼ teaspoon of dried yeast&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also need a grater to grate the ginger, and a plastic funnel. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a funnel, but  you really need one. Trust me on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey idiot, why did you buy a bottle of water instead of using tap water?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; Well, you need  a two litre bottle to make the ginger beer in, and London tap water isn&amp;rsquo;t the nicest in the  world. So I spared no expense and spent 18p on a bottle of Sainsbury&amp;rsquo;s Still Table Water and  killed two birds with one stone. If you already have a clean two litre bottle, and your tap water  is ok, then feel free to use that. Or try a nice expensive mineral water if that sort of thing  tickles your fancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s out of the way, here&amp;rsquo;s what I did next:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/ingredients1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Lay all your ingredients out to make sure you haven&amp;rsquo;t forgotten anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/ingredients2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Realise you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten the yeast, so get that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/decant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Decant the water into a suitable temporary container (skip this step if you are using tap water)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/funnel-sugar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Using a plastic funnel, pour the sugar into the bottle. (if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a funnel fashion one out of paper like me)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/funnel-yeast.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Add the dried yeast to the bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/grating-ginger.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Now, grate the ginger until you have between 1½ and 2 tablespoon&amp;rsquo;s worth. I used 2 tablespoons because I really like ginger, but feel free to vary this according to your tastes. Also, you may wish to cut the skin off before grating. I&amp;rsquo;m lazy so I left it all on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/juicing-lemon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Next, extract the juice from one lemon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/lemon-ginger.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 ) Mix the grated ginger and lemon juice together in a cup or other suitable piece of crockery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/filling-bottle1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Next you need to add the ginger/lemon mixture to the bottle. This is where a plastic funnel comes in really handy. for some reason paper funnels don&amp;rsquo;t work so well once wet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/filling-bottle-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Now, you need to add the water to the bottle. Fill it up until it is about ¾ full, then put the cap on and shake the bottle until all the sugar is dissolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/full-bottle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11) You then need to top the bottle up until there is approximately a one inch gap at the top. This gap is to prevent explosions once the yeast gets to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12) Put the cap on the bottle as tightly as you can, then place the bottle somewhere warm. I put mine in my airing cupboard. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to leave it for 24-48hours to let the yeast go to work. Once the bottle is very hard, and can&amp;rsquo;t be squeezed, the ginger beer is done. It took 24 hours for my batch to be ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13) Place the bottle in the fridge overnight. This halts the yeast and stops the bottle exploding. You really don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave that bottle in a warm place for any longer than 48 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/finished-product.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14) Once the ginger beer is chilled, pour it into a glass and enjoy. I sieve mine when pouring so I don&amp;rsquo;t have any lumps of ginger in the drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there you have it. 2 litres of delicious ginger beer for around 90p and very little effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>