<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Archives on vurt </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 31 May 2013 09:15:40 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewriting history with git</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/rewriting-history-with-git</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 09:15:40 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/rewriting-history-with-git</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when working with git branches, you&amp;rsquo;ll find you need to rewrite history to correct a mistake. For example you squashed your commits into one and pushed them but then realised you&amp;rsquo;d missed something from the squash and need to do it again. Now, while you can perform the git rebase -i again and make the changes locally, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to push this back to origin as your branches have diverged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way of working around this is to delete the remote branch and then push your branch again, essentially overwriting the remote with your version of history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t something that should be done without forethought though, as it has implications for anyone else who may be using the branch but if no one else has done any additional work on the branch then this is relatively safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process for deleting the remote branch is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push origin :branchname&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pushes null to the remote branch, effectively deleting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you want to push your local branch to origin, tracking it in the process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push -u origin branchname&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your branch will now be on origin and your local branch will be tracking it correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone else who has used the branch will want to &lt;code&gt;git reset --hard origin/branchname&lt;/code&gt; in order to get your changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend doing some more reading on this matter before doing it as it&amp;rsquo;s likely that this is all sorts of wrong in the majority of situations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messing about with MRI Data</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/messing-about-with-mri-data</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 15:25:40 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/messing-about-with-mri-data</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve had 2 MRI scans of my left knee as part of ongoing treatment/diagnosis for chronic pain. When discussing my treatment with the consultant, I was intrigued by the images produced by the scanner - detailed images of the inside of my knee from several angles. And thanks to the Data Protection Act, the hospital has to provide me with the data from thescans if I ask for it. So, one quick query at the MRI department, I handed over £10 (The nominal fee to prevent frivolous requests) and walked away with a CD containing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DICOM&#34;&gt;DICOM&lt;/a&gt; image data from both my scans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I have the data but what can I do with it? Surely I&amp;rsquo;ll need some proprietary medical imaging software to view it with? Well on the CD was a windows based viewer program but as a Linux user it&amp;rsquo;s no good to me. Thankfully because DICOM is a ubiquitous standard there are masses of tools available, including many open source offerings. I ended up trying both &lt;a href=&#34;http://ginkgo-cadx.com/en/&#34;&gt;Ginkgocadx&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slicer.org/&#34;&gt;Slicer3D&lt;/a&gt;. Both worked as expected but I ended up sticking with Ginkgocadx - it clicked with me more than Slicer, although that may just be because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to read the Slicer tutorials. Both applications let you view, manipulate and edit the image sequences and they can produce 3Dmodels from the scan data as well, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t explored that option properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve just colourised and converted the image data to make it easier to read and then produced the following pointless (yet strangely engrossing) animated gifs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bones, muscles, tendons and veins in glorious tango-vision!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/2013/01/18/messing-about-with-mri-data/lt_ax_t2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lt_ax_t2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;lt_ax_t2&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/2013/01/18/messing-about-with-mri-data/lt_cor_pd/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lt_cor_pd.gif&#34; alt=&#34;lt_cor_pd&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/2013/01/18/messing-about-with-mri-data/lt_sag_t2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/lt_sag_t2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;lt_sag_t2&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These images came from the most recent scan, I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to convert the ones from before my arthroscopy but I&amp;rsquo;ll do that soon and then see if I can spot the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you fancy having a go yourself but haven&amp;rsquo;t had an MRI scan, then drop me a line and I&amp;rsquo;ll send you an anonymised version of my data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January Frost</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/january-frost</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 18:00:41 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/january-frost</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702198165/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7001/6702198165_cbe590a398.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img_0001_04 by gpaterson&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702198165/&#34;&gt;img_0001_04&lt;/a&gt;, a photo by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/&#34;&gt;gpaterson&lt;/a&gt; on Flickr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went out for a photography walk this morning, after a heavy frost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one turned out rather well I think, might be a candidate for my calendar project&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of others:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702191269/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7023/6702191269_08d8a84ab1_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img_0001_02&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702189313/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7017/6702189313_dd31743099_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img_0001_07&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/6702182167/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7143/6702182167_e2721127f7_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img_0001&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bill-a-soup recipe</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/bill-a-soup-recipe</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 13:34:29 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/bill-a-soup-recipe</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my recipe for delicious bill-a-soup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;450 g broccoli, cut into florets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;175 g  grated cheddar cheese&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;175 g potatoes, chopped&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 medium onion, chopped&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;750 ml chicken stock&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 tablespoon sunflower oil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;pinch Salt and pepper&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;frac12; teaspoon sugar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put the stock in a pan and bring to the boil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour the oil into a large saucepan and fry  the onion gently to soften it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the potatoes to the pan and stir.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the sugar and stock and cook for 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the broccoli and cook until tender, season well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blend the soup in a food processor until smooth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour the soup back into the saucepan,  and stir in the grated cheese.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serve when the cheese has melted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apt behind a proxy</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/apt-behind-a-proxy</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 10:11:56 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/apt-behind-a-proxy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At work, we have to run all our web traffic through an NTLM authenticated proxy, which is a bit of a pain on Linux, requiring us to make use of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cntlm.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;cntlm proxy.&lt;/a&gt; We run this proxy locally on each linux machine (to prevent all traffic appearing as if it comes from one user in the logs), which is fine, but it does cause one or two issues with apt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally I&amp;rsquo;d run apt as &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get ...&lt;/code&gt; but it seems as if the proxy environment variables don&amp;rsquo;t get propagated to the command running under sudo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To work around this, you need to configure apt directly to use a proxy. To do this, create a file in the &lt;code&gt;/etc/apt/apt.conf.d&lt;/code&gt; directory called &lt;code&gt;00proxy&lt;/code&gt;. The file should contain the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;Acquire {
    Retries &amp;quot;0&amp;quot;;
    HTTP {
        Proxy &amp;quot;http://localhost:5865&amp;quot;;
    }
};
&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all apt commands should run successfully through the proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 10.04 Ambiance theme issues with Firefox</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-10-04-ambiance-theme-issues-with-firefox</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 14:20:01 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-10-04-ambiance-theme-issues-with-firefox</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across an interesting issue concerning the default Ubuntu 10.04 Ambiance theme and read only inputs in Firefox today. Basically the foreground and background colours for disabled/read-only input fields are the same, meaning that you can&amp;rsquo;t actually read what&amp;rsquo;s in the fields. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example screen shot from an internal web app I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wmfs.net/&#34;&gt;my employers&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_112&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Disabled inputs in Firefox with the Ubuntu Ambiance theme&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/disabled_inputs_ambiance_crop.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/disabled_inputs_ambiance_crop-300x118.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s what it looks like when using the New Wave theme in Ubuntu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_113&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Disabled inputs in Firefox using the New Wave theme&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/disabled_inputs_new_wave_theme_cropped.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/disabled_inputs_new_wave_theme_cropped-300x118.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issue caused me a few moments of panic when I thought I&amp;rsquo;d broken the app - I was glad it was just a theme glitch! I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to using New Wave for the time being until I can figure out how to get the Ambiance theme to behave properly without screwing the rest of the system colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (2010-05-27):&lt;/strong&gt; Ok, so this turns out to be actually caused by a strange coincidence meaning that our CSS style for disabled inputs had exactly the same colour as the disabled text in the Ambience theme. Since the res of our users are running Windows and IE, it&amp;rsquo;s not a problem. It only affects us developers using Ubuntu :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 10.04 64 bit Eclipse 3.5 Native Proxy support</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-10-04-64-bit-eclipse-3-5-native-proxy-support</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 15:07:31 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-10-04-64-bit-eclipse-3-5-native-proxy-support</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eclipse is a great IDE and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it day to day for a number of years now. However when I recently got a new laptop at work and installed Ubuntu 10.04 on to it, I ran into a problem with the Proxy configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At work, I&amp;rsquo;m stuck behind an NTLM authenticated proxy which I can get my system talking to thanks to running &lt;a href=&#34;http://cntlm.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;cntlm&lt;/a&gt; locally and setting the gnome proxy settings to point to that. On my previous laptop, I was running 32bit Ubuntu and Eclipse just automatically picked up the native proxy info and worked fine. It turns out that this functionality isn&amp;rsquo;t available by default in the 64bit version of Eclipse 3.5. Despite having the option to select &amp;ldquo;Native&amp;rdquo; in the Network Connections preferences in Eclipse, no values are picked up and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect to the outside world to install the extra features I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the solution is to grab the native proxy library from the forthcoming 3.6 version of Eclipse and install it into 3.5, as explained in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/show_bug.cgi?id=273072&#34;&gt;eclipse bug&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did that using the Ubuntu supported version of Eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download the 64 bit Linux version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/packages/release/helios/m6&#34;&gt;Eclipse Classic 3.6.0&lt;/a&gt; (M6 at the time of writing)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Extract it locally and copy the file &lt;code&gt;plugins/org.eclipse.core.net.linux.x86_64_1.1.0.I20091106-0506.jar&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/eclipse/dropins&lt;/code&gt; (you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have to create the dropins directory first).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;/etc/eclipse.ini&lt;/code&gt; to include the following: &lt;code&gt;-Dorg.eclipse.core.net.enableGnome&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delete the eclipse 3.6 directory unless you have a pressing need to keep it around ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you next start eclipse, the Network Connections preferences will be prepopulated with the gnome proxy settings. It took me a while to figure this out, and I&amp;rsquo;ll no doubt need to do it again sometime, so this post is mostly for my own benefit, but hopefully someone else will find it useful too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bootnote: You may be wondering why I didn&amp;rsquo;t just install 3.6 and run that. Well mainly because it&amp;rsquo;s not fully supported by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springsource.com/products/sts&#34;&gt;SpringSource Tool Suite&lt;/a&gt; and also it&amp;rsquo;d mean looking after upgrades and dependencies myself. I&amp;rsquo;d rather have apt handle all that for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Lucid 10.04 Active Directory Woes</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-lucid-10-04-active-directory-woes</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 14:51:45 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-lucid-10-04-active-directory-woes</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was looking forward to the launch of Lucid Lynx as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/testing/lucid/beta2#Major%20new%20version%20of%20likewise-open&#34;&gt;one of the main features being touted&lt;/a&gt; was improved support for joining an Active Directory domain, in the form of Likewise-open. Now this isn&amp;rsquo;t something that most users will care about, but in a corporate environment, allowing users to login to Ubuntu using the same credentials as they use on their windows machines is pretty important. Previously I&amp;rsquo;d set things up manually by configuring Samba and Winbind, but that was a pain in the backside, so Likewise-open was an appealing option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I&amp;rsquo;ve been very disappointed so far. It seems that the version of Likewise-open that ships with Kucid, has a number of glaring bugs that make it virtually pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, there is &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/likewise-open/+bug/534629&#34;&gt;no support for a default domain&lt;/a&gt;. This means that the user has to always log in as user.name@domain or domain\user.name which is a pain. It&amp;rsquo;s not a show stopper but it is trivial to set up using samba, so why can&amp;rsquo;t Likewise support it? Well, Likewise claims to support it, via a registry setting, it&amp;rsquo;s just that it&amp;rsquo;s broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/likewise-open/+bug/572271&#34;&gt;broken credential caching&lt;/a&gt;. Laptops aren&amp;rsquo;t always connected to the domain, so any solution needs to be able to cache credentials to let the user log in when they&amp;rsquo;re out and about. It turns out that the default cache timeout in Likewise is 4 hours. And there&amp;rsquo;s no way to change that. 4 Hours! So that means when you take your laptop home with you at night, intending to work at home the enxt day, you faced with the fact that you can&amp;rsquo;t log in in the morning, or even later that evening. How handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until these issues can be resolved, I&amp;rsquo;m going to purge Likewise and resort to the Samba config method. It&amp;rsquo;s long winded, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s tried and tested and I can actually configure it to work how I need it to. Who knows, maybe Meerkat will have working Likewise, it&amp;rsquo;s just a shame Canonical were touting it as a big improvement in Lucid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, and on a side note, when I upgraded my netbook from 9.10 to 10.04, it killed my wifi and lost the nice netbook remix clutter UI. Ho hum. Time to do a clean install and see if that fixes things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong - I&amp;rsquo;m still a big Ubuntu and Linux fan, I just would have liked this launch to have gone a bit smoother&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu AutoFS Samba/CIFS tweak</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-autofs-sambacifs-tweak</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 14:18:51 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ubuntu-autofs-sambacifs-tweak</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.autofs.org/&#34;&gt;autofs&lt;/a&gt; on my work laptop to automatically mount windows shares when I access them. I achieved this by following &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.howtoforge.com/accessing_windows_or_samba_shares_using_autofs&#34;&gt;this guide on HowtoForge&lt;/a&gt;. Everything runs fine and it means I can do a simple  &lt;code&gt;ls /cifs/machinename&lt;/code&gt; to access all the shares on that particular machine. Provided I&amp;rsquo;d remembered to create a credentials file for that machine name&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The auto.cifs file shown in the howto requires you to create a credentials file for each machine that you want to access. This is handy when the machines you&amp;rsquo;re accessing have different logins, but here at work all machines authenticate against an Active Directory server and so share the same credentials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially I solved this problem by symlinking to the same credential file, but that&amp;rsquo;s still an inconvenience when you need to access a new machine (and boy, do we have a lot of them). Finally I did the sensible thing and altered the auto.cifs file to fallback to a master credentials file if it can&amp;rsquo;t find a machine specific one. Here&amp;rsquo;s my auto.cifs file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;
#!/bin/bash
# This file must be executable to work! chmod 755!
key=&amp;quot;$1&amp;quot;
# Note: create a cred file for each windows/Samba-Server in your network
#       which requires password authentification.  The file should contain
#       exactly two lines:
#          username=user
#          password=*****
#       Please don&#39;t use blank spaces to separate the equal sign from the
#       user account name or password.
credfile=&amp;quot;/etc/auto.smb.$key&amp;quot;
if [ ! -e $credfile ]
then
    credfile=&amp;quot;/etc/auto.smb.master&amp;quot;
fi

# Note: Use cifs instead of smbfs:
mountopts=&amp;quot;-fstype=cifs,file_mode=0644,dir_mode=0755,uid=19654,gid=124&amp;quot;
smbclientopts=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
for P in /bin /sbin /usr/bin /usr/sbin
do
    if [ -x $P/smbclient ]
        then
                SMBCLIENT=$P/smbclient
                break
        fi
done
[ -x $SMBCLIENT ] || exit 1
if [ -e &amp;quot;$credfile&amp;quot; ]
then
        mountopts=$mountopts&amp;quot;,credentials=$credfile&amp;quot;
        smbclientopts=&amp;quot;-A &amp;quot;$credfile
else
        smbclientopts=&amp;quot;-N&amp;quot;
fi
$SMBCLIENT $smbclientopts -gL $key 2&amp;gt;/dev/null \
   | awk -v key=&amp;quot;$key&amp;quot; -v opts=&amp;quot;$mountopts&amp;quot; -F&#39;|&#39; -- &#39;
        BEGIN   { ORS=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;; first=1 }
    /Disk/  { if (first) { print opts; first=0 };
          gsub(/ /, &amp;quot;\\ &amp;quot;, $2);
               sub(/\$/, &amp;quot;\\$&amp;quot;, $2);
                       print &amp;quot; \\\n\t /&amp;quot; $2, &amp;quot;://&amp;quot; key &amp;quot;/&amp;quot; $2 }
        END     { if (!first) print &amp;quot;\n&amp;quot;; else exit 1 }
        &#39;
&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important, and trivial, change is this test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;
if [ ! -e $credfile ]
then
    credfile=&amp;quot;/etc/auto.smb.master&amp;quot;
fi
&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All it does is check for the existence of the credfile. If it can&amp;rsquo;t find it, it uses /etc/auto/smb/master instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of this is that I can use one credentials file for the majority of the file shares yet still provide different credentials for the one or two servers I need to access as a different user (such as an admin user).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oracle/Sun Merger</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/the-oracle-sun-merger</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 10:38:30 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/the-oracle-sun-merger</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, now that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dailyfinance.com/story/european-union-approves-oracle-sun-merger/19328181/&#34;&gt;the EU has approved the Sun/Oracle merger&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2010/01/29/oracle_sun_java_open_source/&#34;&gt;details of which Sun technologies will survive&lt;/a&gt; have started to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First a little history; Oracle bought BEA, makers of Java application server Weblogic, a number of years ago. Sun, obviously, has their own opensource application server Glassfish. Oracle isn&amp;rsquo;t known for their embracing of opensource philosophies so there was a lot of worry that the Sun technologies would get dropped and merely have the good bits integrated into Oracle&amp;rsquo;s products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, Oracle is doing some of that, but they&amp;rsquo;re also keeping the Sun products around but targeting them at a lesser departmental level than Oracle&amp;rsquo;s own offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sun&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://java.sun.com/javase/technologies/hotspot/&#34;&gt;HotSpot&lt;/a&gt; virtual machine is getting merged with Oracle&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technology/products/jrockit/index.html&#34;&gt;JRockit &lt;/a&gt;vm, so now there will be one &amp;ldquo;high performance&amp;rdquo; virtual machine to choose, hopefully better than the separate ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://javafx.com/&#34;&gt;JavaFX&lt;/a&gt;, Sun&amp;rsquo;s attempt at competing with Silverlight and Adobe Flex lives on for some reason. And who knows, maybe Oracle can make it an attractive proposition, lord knows Sun couldn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sun&amp;rsquo;s IDE &lt;a href=&#34;http://netbeans.org/&#34;&gt;NetBeans&lt;/a&gt; lives on, along with &lt;a href=&#34;https://glassfish.dev.java.net/&#34;&gt;Glassfish&lt;/a&gt; but will be target at departmental applications rather than enterprise ones. Oracle&amp;rsquo;s JDeveloper and Weblogic will be marketed as the tools of choice for full scale enterprise apps (mainly because Oracle can charge for Weblogic, I would guess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully&lt;a href=&#34;http://hudson-ci.org/&#34;&gt; Hudson&lt;/a&gt;, Sun&amp;rsquo;s open source continuous integration and deployment server/tool lives on under Oracle&amp;rsquo;s ownership. This is particularly good news for me as I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at that for improving the Java development and deployment at my employers (I&amp;rsquo;d have hated to have gone down that route only to find the product is being mothballed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for development of Java as a language, Oracle now has main control over the Java SE, EE and ME specifications and they&amp;rsquo;ve committed to adding more staff and money to developing them, which is good. Although it remains to be seen which directions Oracle will choose to take the language in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I notice that the Sun website has now been Oracle-ised, which means it&amp;rsquo;ll probably end up being as painful to navigate as Oracle&amp;rsquo;s. Look forward to URLs changing on a weekly basis and bookmarks to help pages and so on dying regularly!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study with the Open University using Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/study-with-the-open-university-using-ubuntu</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 19:32:03 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/study-with-the-open-university-using-ubuntu</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently enrolled with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.open.ac.uk/&#34;&gt;Open University&lt;/a&gt; for the first time, to study Software Project Management. The first course I&amp;rsquo;m taking is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www3.open.ac.uk/study/postgraduate/course/m865.htm&#34;&gt;M865 Project Management&lt;/a&gt; and ultimately I&amp;rsquo;m studying towards the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www3.open.ac.uk/study/postgraduate/qualification/E19.htm&#34;&gt;Postgraduate Diploma in Management of Software Projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OU is pretty heavily geared towards using Microsoft Windows and associated software when studying and submitting assignments, and I&amp;rsquo;m strictly a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu &lt;/a&gt;kind of guy, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to be in for a few issues along the way, no doubt. I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to use Linux alternatives wherever possible, falling back to WINE to run Windows applications if I have to and I&amp;rsquo;ll document my progress here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M865 requires you to use project management software to do some of the assignments and activities, and you&amp;rsquo;re provided with a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciforma.com/page?id=303&#34;&gt;Sciforma PS8&lt;/a&gt; to do this. Thankfully, this installs and runs fine using WINE, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use that if none of the open source alternatives work, but I intend to investigate the linux native options such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://live.gnome.org/Planner&#34;&gt;Planner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.taskjuggler.org/&#34;&gt;Taskjuggler&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://openproj.org/openproj&#34;&gt;Openproj&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have managed to find and install a linux version of the FirstClass messaging software that the OU use for discussion forums. Whilst you can access the forums via the website, the functionality is reduced and it&amp;rsquo;s not so nice to use. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intl.firstclass.com/ClientDownloads/Linux%20Download%20Page&#34;&gt;debian package&lt;/a&gt; available, along with a generic linux archive. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple case of installing that package and running it on Ubuntu 9.10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time you run it, you need to click on the advanced link on the login screen to configure the server to use, this will be either oufcnt1.open.ac.uk or oufcnt2.open.ac.uk. Try both if you have authentication problems, you may not have an account on both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up I&amp;rsquo;m going to investigate the eTMA assignment submission system and see if there&amp;rsquo;s anything specific I need to do for that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ilford HP3 Panchromatic Found Film</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ilford-hp3-panchromatic-found-film</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 20:26:15 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/ilford-hp3-panchromatic-found-film</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I bought a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brownie-camera.com/54.shtml&#34;&gt;Kodak No2 Box Brownie&lt;/a&gt; on ebay with the intention of hacking it about for a project. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, it was listed as broken and indeed the shutter was shot - I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t destroy a functioning camera!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/3407073245/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3335/3407073245_0167ec699d_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;panchromatic&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
The camera and the film I found inside it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst cleaning the camera I opened it up and found that it still had a roll of film inside. The film label stated it was Ilford HP3 Panchromatic, which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.photomemorabilia.co.uk/Ilford/Chronology.html&#34;&gt;turns out&lt;/a&gt; to be a forerunner to the current HP5 film, first introduced in 1942 before being replaced by HP4 in 1965.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/3406952773/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3570/3406952773_379d4e3710_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;snow_drift3&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
One of the snow drift shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never processed old film before, and at between 40 and 50 years old, this film was pretty damn old. However, google revealed that in similar situations, this type of film had &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.halfhill.com/future.html&#34;&gt;produced decent results&lt;/a&gt;. Following the advice of others, I decided to develop the film in ID-11 for double the length of time stated for HP5 Plus (the modern equivalent of this film).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was worried that the film would be brittle or that the emulsion would have crumbled off, but aside from being very curly and a little tacky, the film loaded and developed just fine. I think that double the time might have been too much, as the film came out very dark, but otherwise it was ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/3407759736/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3614/3407759736_9f6c86c8b4_m.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;house_construction3&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
The house build in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what was on the roll? Well half of it contained pictures of an extensio being built on a house, and the other half were shots of some deep snow drifts and trees. Not hugely exciting but interesting none the less. I&amp;rsquo;m going to contact the ebay seller and see if they want the negatives, I&amp;rsquo;ll also email them the hi-res scans that I&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the whole set of images on my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/gpaterson/tags/ilfordhp3/&#34;&gt;flickr account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrambled Eggs and the Art of Recruitment</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/scrambled-eggs-recruitment</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 12:30:13 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/scrambled-eggs-recruitment</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve done a round of recruitment for a 12 month temporary Java developer role for my employers and so I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot on how best to determine the skills and ability of a candidate. Incidentally, if anyone was in any doubt as to the harsh ecnomic climate we&amp;rsquo;re in, we received 77 applicants for this position, normally we get around 12&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our standard recruitment process is to shortlist based on CVs, telephone interview the shortlist and then get the best 3 or 4 in for face to face interviews. After the interview I get the candidates to write a simple bit of java code, the problem they&amp;rsquo;re given is to implement a number guessing game, essentially &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of a number between 1 and 10&amp;rdquo;.  It&amp;rsquo;s a simple task, particularly when they&amp;rsquo;re given certain pointers in the problem description, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found it is a useful indicator of the candidate&amp;rsquo;s ability. I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for perfect solutions, rather I&amp;rsquo;m looking at how they&amp;rsquo;ve approached the problem and how they&amp;rsquo;ve thought about the issues involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far this approach has worked well for us and I&amp;rsquo;ve been very happy with the people we&amp;rsquo;ve recruited so far, however I do wonder if the technical test is entirely suitable. Is it challenging enough or do we need different levels of technical test depending on the seniority of the role we&amp;rsquo;re recruiting for? Can technical tests be realistic enough to give a good impression or should we embrace the artificial nature of the setup?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m fairly sure there is no right or wrong answer to this and veryone I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken to has had a different opinion on the subject. Recently though, I found out that even Gordon Ramsey uses a similar trivial test when he takes on a new chef in one of his kitchens. He gets them to make scrambled eggs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea being, that if they can make great scrambled eggs, then it shows that they know what they&amp;rsquo;re talking about and will be a good chef.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now like to think of my technical test as equivalent to making great scrambled eggs. If a candidate can come up with a great solution or implementation of the number guessing game, then they should be a great developer. Of course, not everyone likes scrambled eggs&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technotrend S-1500 CI and Mythtv Remote Control</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/technotrend-s-1500-ci-and-mythtv-remote-control</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 16:18:43 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/technotrend-s-1500-ci-and-mythtv-remote-control</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in January, I built myself a PVR using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mythtv.org/&#34;&gt;MythTV&lt;/a&gt; (I went for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mythbuntu.org/&#34;&gt;Mythbuntu&lt;/a&gt; distribution to simplify things) and have been very happy with it on the most part. However a recent distribution upgrade from Ubuntu Hardy to Ubuntu Intrepid left me with a non-working remote control which was not ideal, to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a bit of background, I&amp;rsquo;m using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technotrend.de/2763/TT-budget__S-1500.html&#34;&gt;Technotrend S-1500&lt;/a&gt; tv capture card to receive free-to-air  satellite transmissions here in the UK (aside: I originally chose this card because it came with a CI slot which I could use with a Dragon CAM to get subscription services from Sky - a not supported configuraiton but working according to my research. However with the release of FreeSat, I decided not to bother and stick to the free to air services, including BBC HD and 8 day program guide). This card comes with a little IR eye and a remote control to make interacting with Mythtv easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Configuring Lirc took a bit of trial and error because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a configuration file for the remote control. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of documentation out there on how to configure Lirc, that assumes you have a more common remote. One of the best guides is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parker1.co.uk/mythtv_ubuntu2.php&#34;&gt;Garry Parker&amp;rsquo;s MythTv guide&lt;/a&gt;, which includes a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parker1.co.uk/mythtv_tips.php&#34;&gt;nice tip&lt;/a&gt; on ensuring your remote receiver get allocated the same id each time. However, without the lircd.conf file, you need to create one using irrecord. For me it was a case of running this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;irrecord --driver=dev/input --device=/dev/input/event6 lircd.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the onscreen prompts and away you go, using that file in your lirc configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This served me well until the aforementioned system upgrade to Ubuntu Intrepid.  My remote suddenly stopped working, except for the arrow keys and the 0-9 numbers. I went back over the configuratiosn with a fine toothed comb but everything seemed to be correct. I thought that maybe the signal from the remote was being interpreted differently, so I decided to try regenerating the configuration file with irrecord but now irrecord was telling me it couldn&amp;rsquo;t get exclusive access to the hardware, despite me shutting down mythtv and lircd! Something was very wrong&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a lot of searching, I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/ubuntu/+source/lirc/+bug/204960&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; that shed light on the problem and gave me a solution. Essentially, X was grabbing control of the input and treating it like a keyboard, which is why the number buttons and arrow buttons were working but nothing else. The solution is to enter your car&amp;rsquo;d product string into the &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/hal/fdi/preprobe/20thirdparty/lirc.fdi&lt;/code&gt; file as an exception. This mean X will ignore the input and let Lirc handle it instead. Annoyingly, my card is based on the saa7134 chipset and there was an exception for those card already in the lirc.fdi file. Unfortunately, my card&amp;rsquo;s product string is &amp;ldquo;Budget-CI dvb ir receiver saa7146 (0)&amp;rdquo; which didn&amp;rsquo;t match, so I needed to add another one&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I now have a working remote control, which is nice, but I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel that this is a bit of a backwards step, in that these devices worked before the changes to the HAL system and now, a fairly large list of exceptions needs to be maintained to ensure that cards continue to function as they used to. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are good reasons for the changes but it&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that as an end user I just find irritating :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porting Django to 1.0 from an earlier version</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/porting-django-to-10-from-an-earlier-version</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 15:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/archive/porting-django-to-10-from-an-earlier-version</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.c4mbodia.com/&#34;&gt;personal web development project&lt;/a&gt; and whilst it is a lovely framework, it&amp;rsquo;s been undergoing very active development to get it to a 1.0 release. The previous release was 0.96 but that was sometime before I started my project, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working to a version checked out of subversion around 4 months ago which contained some new features but not everything that eventually made it into 1.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of my recent desire to sort my life out and get more things done, I&amp;rsquo;ve been adding features to my project and have decided to get it running in django 1.0. Now, as I was using a version of django part way between 0.96 and 1.0 I didn&amp;rsquo;t have as much work to do as I anticipated, which was nice. What was even nicer, was this helpful &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/releases/1.0-porting-guide/&#34;&gt;guide to porting&lt;/a&gt; on the excellent django documentation site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was already suing the newforms module, a few renames later had me working using the forms name instead. And most of my other changes were fairly minor as well, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I decided to use a post-0.96 version when I started my project otherwise I&amp;rsquo;d have had a fair bit more work to do. The most major changes came with the Admin functionality for my models as this has changed quite significantly. It&amp;rsquo;s all well documented though, so an hour or so later I had some new admin.py files detailing the admin interfaces to my models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did run in to two stumbling points though. I use modified pre-order tree traversal for a number of my models and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/django-mptt/&#34;&gt;third-party implementation&lt;/a&gt; I was using wasn&amp;rsquo;t playing nice with the new django admin stuff. However, a quick svn checkout of the latest revision got me past that problem. The second stumbling block was with getting my user profile models to be displayed inline with the django authentication User model in the admin interface. The trick is to first unregister the User model from the admin site and then re-register it with my own admin class:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;``&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;from django.contrib import admin
from django.contrib.auth.models import User
from django.contrib.auth.admin import UserAdmin

from users.models import UserProfile

admin.site.unregister(User)

# Set it up so we can edit a user&#39;s profile inline in the admin
class UserProfileInline(admin.StackedInline):
    fields = (&#39;donated&#39;, &#39;tagline&#39;, &#39;birthday&#39;, &#39;profile&#39;)
    model = UserProfile

class MyUserAdmin(UserAdmin):
    inlines = [UserProfileInline]

# re-register the User with the extended admin options
admin.site.register(User, MyUserAdmin)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that was it - I now have a version of my site ready to roll with django 1.0&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>