<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Projects on vurt </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://vurt.co.uk/project/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 09:05:45 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a scaffold plank table</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/project/table_top</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 09:05:45 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/project/table_top</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while now, I&amp;rsquo;ve fancied having a nice little bistro-style table to go on the patio in my garden but was unable to find anything that I liked. As I had a some 7ft scaffold planks left over from building some raised beds, I decided to use one of those and make my own table top. At this point, the plan was to use a standard table base and just make my own top, but more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now scaffold planks aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly high quality building materials as they will be bettered, bent and probably covered in building dust. Here&amp;rsquo;s the one I started with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2153.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2153_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;A scaffold plank&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first job is to remove the protective metal straps at either end of the board. They&amp;rsquo;ll probably be held in with half a dozen nails and can be pried free quite easily:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2156.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2156_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Metal straps - watch out as they&#39;re sharp!&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now as any skilled woodworker will tell you, it&amp;rsquo;s important to properly prepare your timber for the job in hand. So you&amp;rsquo;ll want to pass the plank through a thickness planer to get rid of any bowing and then ensure the sides are straight and true by carefully planing them with a jointing plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, if you&amp;rsquo;re me just bung the plank in to your workmate and attack the edges with your electric plane and hope for the best:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2157.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2157_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Perfectly straight planed edges are what you&#39;re aiming for.&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to cut your plank to size. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to measure the width of the planed board and multiply this appropriately so you get three sections, resulting in a square table top. My table top measures 60cm square which is a nice size for a table for two people to sit in the sun on the patio enjoying a nice cool drink&amp;hellip; Anyway, once you&amp;rsquo;ve cut the board, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2160.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2160_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dry run arrangement&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to use dowel joints to fix my boards together. This is a simple case of drilling holes in each plank, sitting the dowel markers in the holes then offering up the next plank for marking so you know where to drill. There are a number of dowel jointing kits and jigs available that make this easier/more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to drill your holes. I&amp;rsquo;m using 8mm dowels so that means (amazingly) an 8mm wood drill bit, fitted with a depth stop:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2162.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2162_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Holes everywhere&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then fit the spiked metal markers into the holes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2164.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2164_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Caution: Sharp!&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you offer up the next board and press it firmly against the markers. You&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a series of dimples in the board that show where you need to drill. This will ensure that your holes line up nicely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2166.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2166_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cute dimples&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next stage is to liberally apply wood glue to the holes and the sides of each board, sit the dowels in place then push the various boards together:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2168.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2168_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Glue and dowels&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, clamp it all together and leave to dry overnight:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2172.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/table/top/DSCF2172_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Clamped in place&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing up what I did for the base and how I attached the top in later posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing a Defender Mudflap</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/project/defender_mudflap</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 20:21:04 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/project/defender_mudflap</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Landrover Defender 110 lost one of its rear mudflaps a while back and was looking rather tatty as a result. So after a few months of putting the job off, I finally bought some replacement rubber and set about putting things right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old flap had torn off, leaving a stub still attached to the bracket by a couple of rivets: &lt;a href=&#34;/images/landrover/mudflap/DSCF1944.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/landrover/mudflap/DSCF1944_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Torn off mudflap&#34; title=&#34;Torn off mudflap&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old rubber must have come loose previously as one of the rivets was replaced witha  nut and bolt. I removed that and drilled out the two remaining rivets to be left with an empty bracket: &lt;a href=&#34;/images/landrover/mudflap/DSCF1951.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/landrover/mudflap/DSCF1951_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bracket with old rivets removed&#34; title=&#34;Bracket with old rivets removed&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was simply a case of attaching the replacement rubber to the bracket using new M6 bolts and locking nuts and a couple of large repair washers to hold everything in place, as shown here: &lt;a href=&#34;/images/landrover/mudflap/DSCF1952.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/landrover/mudflap/DSCF1952_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bolt and washer arrangement&#34; title=&#34;Bolt and washer arrangement&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The job took a total of about 30 minutes and most of that was because my cordless drill ran out of juice as it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really powerful enough to drill out the rivets, meaning I had to dig out my big corded drill. I&amp;rsquo;m pleased with the result as balance has been restored to the rear of my truck: &lt;a href=&#34;/images/landrover/mudflap/DSCF1958.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/landrover/mudflap/DSCF1958_thumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Balance restored!&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a log store</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/project/building-a-log-store</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 22:02:55 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/project/building-a-log-store</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had a wood burning stove installed which meant that I needed somewhere to store all the logs I&amp;rsquo;ll be burning. Rather than spend a lot of money on a professionally made log store, I decided to make my own, because hey, I own a hammer and a saw, how hard can it be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sketched a rough plan on the bag of an envelope then headed down to my nearest large hardware retailer and picked up some supplies:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_113251.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_113251-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_113251&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
I decided to use a 6&amp;rsquo;x3&amp;rsquo; lattice fence panel as the back of the log store because I was feeling lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a simple base, using five cross pieces to take the weight of the logs and form the feet of the store:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_121656.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_121656-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_121656&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the base was done, it was time to make the sides. Since I was using a 6&amp;rsquo;x3&amp;rsquo; panel for the back, I made the rear uprights just over 3&amp;rsquo; tall and the front ones around 4&amp;rsquo;. Throw in a couple of braces and then nail the back in place and I&amp;rsquo;m left with this: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_131014.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_131014-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_131014&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the roof, I added horizontal beams to the front and rear uprights then added 4 rafters, making sure to accurately measure and cut the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birdsmouth_joint&#34;&gt;birdsmouth joints&lt;/a&gt;. I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t sloppily mark and then eyeball the cuts with a junior hacksaw, oh no:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_142355.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_142355-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_142355&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt; I made sure to leave an overhang so the finished roof would extend in front of the store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the roof out of featheredge fence boards, nailing them to the rafters and making sure they overlap each other by around 50%. Fence boards were also used for the sides, makign sure to leave gaps to allow for air circulation: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_161531.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130216_161531-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130216_161531&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was the store made, then it was just a case of moving it into position then stacking all the logs up, making sure to leave room for the cat&amp;rsquo;s house since the store is going against the wall where the cat house normally sits:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130217_143339.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_20130217_143339-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20130217_143339&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I&amp;rsquo;m pretty pleased with it, it may not be perfect but it does the job and it looks the part. I&amp;rsquo;ve filled it with just over 1 cubic metre of logs and there&amp;rsquo;s room for a bit more should I need it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Make Ginger Beer</title>
      <link>http://vurt.co.uk/project/gingerbeer</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2005 16:46:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vurt.co.uk/project/gingerbeer</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I fancied a nice cool drink the other night, but I&amp;rsquo;m fed up with cola, lemonade and juices.
I prefer a &amp;ldquo;drier&amp;rdquo; soft drink, and one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make you want to scrub your teeth
immediately after drinking. So I decided to make myself some ginger beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hang on, why didn&amp;rsquo;t you just buy some ginger beer?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; I imagine you asking me. Well, most  commercially produced ginger beer is far too sweet and not gingery enough for my taste,  that is why. And I was bored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;rsquo;s what I used to make a delicious ginger beverage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 litre bottle of still mineral water&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;large chunk of root ginger (you need 1½ to 2 tablespoons of grated ginger)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 lemon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 cup of sugar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;¼ teaspoon of dried yeast&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also need a grater to grate the ginger, and a plastic funnel. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a funnel, but  you really need one. Trust me on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey idiot, why did you buy a bottle of water instead of using tap water?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; Well, you need  a two litre bottle to make the ginger beer in, and London tap water isn&amp;rsquo;t the nicest in the  world. So I spared no expense and spent 18p on a bottle of Sainsbury&amp;rsquo;s Still Table Water and  killed two birds with one stone. If you already have a clean two litre bottle, and your tap water  is ok, then feel free to use that. Or try a nice expensive mineral water if that sort of thing  tickles your fancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s out of the way, here&amp;rsquo;s what I did next:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/ingredients1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Lay all your ingredients out to make sure you haven&amp;rsquo;t forgotten anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/ingredients2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Realise you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten the yeast, so get that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/decant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Decant the water into a suitable temporary container (skip this step if you are using tap water)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/funnel-sugar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Using a plastic funnel, pour the sugar into the bottle. (if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a funnel fashion one out of paper like me)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/funnel-yeast.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Add the dried yeast to the bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/grating-ginger.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) Now, grate the ginger until you have between 1½ and 2 tablespoon&amp;rsquo;s worth. I used 2 tablespoons because I really like ginger, but feel free to vary this according to your tastes. Also, you may wish to cut the skin off before grating. I&amp;rsquo;m lazy so I left it all on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/juicing-lemon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Next, extract the juice from one lemon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/lemon-ginger.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 ) Mix the grated ginger and lemon juice together in a cup or other suitable piece of crockery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/filling-bottle1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) Next you need to add the ginger/lemon mixture to the bottle. This is where a plastic funnel comes in really handy. for some reason paper funnels don&amp;rsquo;t work so well once wet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/filling-bottle-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) Now, you need to add the water to the bottle. Fill it up until it is about ¾ full, then put the cap on and shake the bottle until all the sugar is dissolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/full-bottle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11) You then need to top the bottle up until there is approximately a one inch gap at the top. This gap is to prevent explosions once the yeast gets to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12) Put the cap on the bottle as tightly as you can, then place the bottle somewhere warm. I put mine in my airing cupboard. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to leave it for 24-48hours to let the yeast go to work. Once the bottle is very hard, and can&amp;rsquo;t be squeezed, the ginger beer is done. It took 24 hours for my batch to be ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13) Place the bottle in the fridge overnight. This halts the yeast and stops the bottle exploding. You really don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave that bottle in a warm place for any longer than 48 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.vurt.co.uk/images/gingerbeer/finished-product.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14) Once the ginger beer is chilled, pour it into a glass and enjoy. I sieve mine when pouring so I don&amp;rsquo;t have any lumps of ginger in the drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there you have it. 2 litres of delicious ginger beer for around 90p and very little effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>